Think about the crunch of celery, mixed with a smooth, creamy tzatziki or the tang of a spicy salsa piled on top of a crispy corn tortilla chip.
想象一下芹菜的脆爽，混合着顺滑、奶油般的希腊酸奶黄瓜酱，或者是堆在酥脆玉米片上的辣味莎莎酱的浓郁酸味。
Is anything more satisfying to eat than a dip?
还有什么比蘸酱食品更令人满足的食物吗？
Dips have become big business.
调味酱已经成了一门大生意。
In 2022, over £263 million pounds were spent on dips, just in the UK.
仅在2022年，英国就在调味酱上花费了超过2.63亿英镑。
Why is it that we like them so much?
为什么我们如此喜欢它们呢？
Food writer Ben Paynter cites studies showing that modern restaurants use cooking techniques that can leave food seeming dry, but that sauces and dips can replace the lost moisture.
美食作家本·佩恩特引用的研究表明，现代餐厅使用的烹饪技术可能会让食物显得干涩，而酱汁和蘸酱可以补充流失的水分。
Some studies have even suggested, that the liquid nature of dips and sauces brings flavours into contact with more of our taste buds, intensifying them.
一些研究甚至表明，蘸酱和酱汁的液体性质能让风味接触到我们更多的味蕾，从而增强味道。
Our love for dips could be driven by positive associations.
我们对调味酱的喜爱可能是因为正向关联性。
Dips are designed to be shared and eaten without cutlery, they can feel more communal and informal.
蘸酱的设计初衷就是供人分享，无需餐具即可食用，因此更具共享性和非正式感。
Diners may associate them with happy social occasions.
用餐者可能会将它们与愉快的社交场合联系起来。
British food writer Clare Finney points out that when dips first became popular in the UK, people may have related them to popular holiday destinations.
英国美食作家克莱尔·芬尼指出，当调味酱首次在英国流行时，人们可能会将它们与热门度假目的地联系起来。
Communal shared eating may be good for our mental health, but what do dips do to our physical health?
共同分享食物可能对我们的心理健康有益，但调味酱对我们的身体健康有何影响呢？
Dieticians have raised different arguments.
营养学家们提出了不同的观点。
One considers that dips encourage people to include more vegetables in their diet.
一种观点认为，蘸酱鼓励人们在饮食中加入更多蔬菜。
The opposing argument is that dips can be high in saturated fat, calories, and salt.
相反的观点是，蘸酱可能含有高饱和脂肪、高热量和高盐分。
Many dips have small recommended portion sizes, but that doesn't mean that people follow this guidance.
许多调味酱的建议食用分量都很小，但这并不意味着人们会遵循这一指导。
One US study found that 48% of those surveyed admitted to finishing an entire container in one sitting.
美国一项研究发现，48%的受访者承认会一次性吃完一整盒调味酱。
Djin Gie Liem, a sensory science professor, points out that people are less likely to become accustomed to the taste of healthy food if they only eat it covered in sauce.
感官科学教授林锦杰指出，如果人们只吃裹满酱汁的健康食品，他们就不太可能习惯健康食品本身的味道。
Dips can bring good social times to mind and give us intense flavours.
调味酱能让人想起美好的社交时光，并带来浓郁的风味。
Maybe we just need to pay a little bit more attention to the suggested portion sizes.
也许我们只需要对建议的食用分量多留意一点就行了。